Pray Away is a documentary film directed by Kristine Stolakis.
In the 1970s, five men struggling with being gay in their Evangelical church started a bible study to help each other leave the "homosexual lifestyle." They quickly received over
25,000 letters from people asking for help and formalized as Exodus International, the largest and most controversial conversion therapy organization in the world.
But leaders struggled with a secret: their own
“same-sex attractions” never went away.
After years as Christian superstars in the religious right, many of these men and women
have come out as LGBTQ, disavowing the very movement they helped start.
Focusing on the dramatic journeys of former conversion therapy leaders, current members, and a survivor, PRAY AWAY
chronicles the “ex gay" movement’s rise to power, persistent influence, and the profound harm it causes.
Self, played by Julie Rodgers.
Self, played by Randy Thomas.
Self, played by Yvette Cantu Schneider.
Self, played by John Paulk.
Self, played by Jeffrey McCall.
Self, played by Alan Chambers.
Pray Away is a 2021 American documentary film
produced and directed by Kristine Stolakis.
It follows survivors of conversion therapy, and former leaders.
Jason Blum and Ryan Murphy serve as executive producers.
It had its world premiere at the Tribeca Film Festival on June 16, 2021.
It was released on August 3, 2021, by Netflix.
The film explores themes of homophobia, guilt, lgbt,
woman director, conversion therapy.